YYeTs人人影视字幕组出品
最新最快字幕下载请登录：www.YYeTs.net
■
字幕：YYeTs人人影视字幕组  后期：梁良
告诉你那渔夫 书在斯科菲尔德的哥哥手上
Tell your fisherman friend Scofield's brother has this.
放过惠斯勒吧
Just take the bounty off Whistler.
惠斯勒对我而言没有利用价值
Whistler don't mean nothing to me, man.
我可以帮上很多忙
There are ways I can be of assistance.
惠斯勒现在清白了吧
Whistler's clear?
和天空一样清白 兄弟
Clear as the blue sky, brother.
那么我们怎么出去
So, how are we getting out of here?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
你在这干什么?
What the hell are you doing?
我只是
I just
我需要点钱 还有我
I need some money, and I didn't
我也不知道可以去哪里
I didn't know where else to go.
我有大概$50
I've got about $50.
不
Nono.
老兄 我指的是那几百万
I'm talking about the millions, papi.
背包呢?
The backpack?
所有的钱都在里面
There's all sorts of cash in that thing.
需要个地方躲下 我帮你 但是背包没了
Need a place to crash,I got your back,but the backpack's gone.
我的那份是给我弟弟的
Any money I dig out is for my brother.
记得他吗
Remember him?
高高的个子 有点瘦
Tall guy, kind of thin.
帮你越狱
Busted your ass out of jail.
我觉得欠他的情
I feel bad about Mike.
真的 林肯
I do, Linc.
不是所有人都可以被赦免的
But not all of us got exonerated, you know.
非常清楚
Pretty clear on that.
我现在甚至都不能回家
I can't ever go home again.
你有麻烦吗 苏克雷?
You got problems, Sucre?
林肯 不是只有你有麻烦
You ain't the only one,Linc.
对
That's right.
我们某种程度上都有罪
We're all guilty of something, man.
我们所有人
All of us.
但他们不是
Not them.
我需要帮助
I want to help.
但是看起来只是越陷越深
But it seems like it's only getting deeper and deeper.
我只是想要些钱 然后重新开始
Look, I just, I just want money to get back on my feet and that's it, Linc.
林肯
Linc?
算了
Never mind.
人性泯灭到兽性大发 用不了多久
Doesn't take too long for a man to become animal, no?
聪明人会先去占他的床位
The smart ones go for his bunk first.
那笨人会干嘛?
What do the dumb ones do?
嘿 我先来的
Hey, I was here first.
贱人 你来这才两天而已
Mampi bitch, you been here two days.
我是说 我第一个拿到他的鞋的
I meant I was the first one to the shoe,
你个装大胸的家伙 拿过来
you sack-in-the-box now hand it over.
你是不是要个鸡爪来决斗
You're asking for a chicken foot, friend.
想要鞋是吗
You want this shoe?
那就放马过来吧
You're gonna have to come and get it.
让他过来
Leave him. Leave him.
我只是想表达我的谢意
I just wanted to express my thanks
为
for, uh
为惠斯勒的事
for Whistler.
我不知道你在说什么
I'm afraid I have no idea what you're talking about.
对不起我的错
My mistake.
另外 或许我们能重新做些安排
Anyway, I thought maybe we could make some kind of arrangement.
也许我能
Maybe I could
在这帮上什么忙
help out around Sona.
过来哥们
Come here, boy.
你们过去
Leave.
你来帮我?
You help me?
我是这的老大
I'm the bucky massa here, boy.
是我 不是你
Me. Not you.
任何人想在索纳监狱要东西 只能来找我
So if anyone want anything at Sona, it's me them will come to.
所以不要到这来 说什么能帮忙
So do not walk in here asking for some favor
好像我们有什么共识似的 不 没有
like we have some understanding. No, no, no, no, no.
根本没有
We do not.
小子 下次你再来这一套
The next time you roll in here like that, boy,
你只能乞求我能仁慈点
the only thing you ask me for is mercy.
明白了吗
Si?
斯科菲尔德 有访客
Scofield, visitor.
去吧 小子
Go on, boy.
现在 去吧 你妈妈在找你呢
Now, run along, your momma calling ya.
不妙 对吧
That bad, huh?
很不妙
It's not good.
你呢
You?
我追查你从惠斯勒那得到信息
I followed that message you got from Whiler.
全是关于一本书的
It's all about some book.
鸟类导读 上面有名字和号码
A bird guide. Names and numbers on it.
有关于他身份的线索吗
Any clues as about who he might be?
还没 我们不是唯一在追查他的人
No. We weren't the only ones following his directions.
他女友也在列 称他是个渔夫
His girl was there, says he's some kind of fisherman.
对 最好他是
Yeah, sure he is.
听着 伙计 我 我想给你看些东西
Listen, man, I, uh, I want you to check something out.
我的天啊
Oh, my God
她举着报纸的姿势
The way she's holding the paper
就好像她在
it's like she's, uh,
好像她在指着什么
it's like she's pointing at something.
太小了 我看不清
It's too small I can't read it.
是今天的报纸
This is today's paper.
她指着圣丽塔
She's pointing at Santa Rita.
那是离这20英里远的小镇
It's a small town 20 miles from here.
她在试着告诉我们她在哪
She's trying to tell us where she is.
我得跟她说话 林肯
I have to talk to her, Linc.
就算他们让你跟她通话 伙计
Even if they let you talk to her, man,
他们也会监听你的每字每句
they'll be listening to every word you say.
你不能这么做
You can't do that.
除了地名 我们还需要更多信息
We're gonna need more than the name of that town.
我至今还是什么办法都没有 林肯
I'm coming up empty-handed here, Linc.
已经3天了
It's already been three days and
而我一筹莫展
I got nothing to show for it.
所以 如果我不能把惠斯勒从这救出去
So, if I can't break Whistler out of here
你必须得把他们从那救出来
you're gonna have to break them out of there.
那么 计划是什么 伙伴?
So, what's the deal, mate?
什么时候行动
When's moving day?
你告诉我你是谁 我就告诉你计划
I'll tell you the plan when you tell me who you are.
-我是个渔夫 -是吗
-I'm a fisherman. -Really?
我也是
So am I.
你还在担心我是否值得信赖?
You're worried about trusting me?
我的命掌握在你的手里
My life is in your hands.
我怎么知道我是不是该信任你
How am I supposed to know that I can trust you?
你不要知道
You don't.
斯图尔特·斯科特
Hey. Stuart Scott.
一号 对吧? 你看体育中心吗?
Number one, right? You watch the SportsCenter?
最近没有 听着 我需要打个电话
Not recently. Look, I need to get my hands on a phone.
我还想要摸女人呢
I need to get my hands on some pechos.
但是那是不可能实现的 对吧
But that ain't gonna happen either, is it?
再说 谁那么重要 你必须得打给她
Who you got to call so important anyway?
莎拉
Sara
绝对不可能
Absolutely not.
这不是个请求 而是命令
It ain't a request; it's a dictation of terms.
我弟弟不会想办法越狱 除非他跟莎拉通话
My brother ain't thinking about escape till he talks to Sara.
真甜蜜
Aw, that's sweet.
我可以向你保证2件事 林肯
I can assure you of two things, Lincoln.
第一 莎拉没事
One, that Sara's fine
第二 你可以把我打翻在场
and two, you have a better chance of banging me on that bar
但绝不能和她通话
than you do of talking to her.
感谢你的提议 但是我拒绝
I appreciate the offer, but I'll pass.
-确定? -确定
Yeah? Yeah.
但如果这是个命令呢
Oh, what if that's a dictation of terms.
这根本没有协商的余地
It's not a matter of negotiaon.
政府把这里的电话拆了精光
Government rip out all the phones
当发现这帮罪人在索纳监狱依然恶性不改
when they find out bad men in Sona still setting up deals.
还像过去那样闹个不停
Making bang-bangs just like before.
他们就把电话线切断了
They just did it over the phone.
如果是切断线路的话 或许能修复
Well, if they cut the lines, maybe we can fix 'em.
大哥 没什么好修的
There's nothing to fix, bro.
这里以前沿着墙根都是成卷的电话线
There used to be a whole row of them all along the wall,
但是现在都没有了
but they're gone now.
如果你没有问题了
If you have no more questions
我就走了
I'm just gonna get going.
迈克两天内就救下了惠斯勒的命
Michael got the bounty off Whistler's head in two days.
那是你们的人两周都办不到的
That's more than your people could do in two weeks.
来点诚意吧
Show some goodwill.
当他救出惠斯勒后 会得到的
He'll get his goodwill when Whistler's out.
这点你必须了解下我弟弟
One thing you should know about my brother,
那就是他很顽固
he's very stubborn.
要想有收获 必须先付出
You want him to fetch, you throw him a bone.
那么让迈克在狱内通个电话怎样?
How does Michael think he's gonna get his hands on a phone inside Sona?
那手机呢?
What about cell phones?
这边人来人往的 可以带个混进来
With all the traffic moving in and out of here.
手机想都别想
Cell phone big no-no.
只有一个人有权有手机
Only one man has access to it,
而他绝不会给你这样的家伙用
and he would never let a zanahoria like you
让我猜猜是谁
Let me guess.
这是什么?
What is it?
外头给你的本周行动指示
The weekly from your operations on the outside.
低调行事
Grave digger dropped it off.
这可办不到
That couldn't be.
这薄薄的信封就打发我了
This envelope way too thin.
东西运输上最近有点慢
Stuff just moving a little slow on the outside these days.
是吗 东西运得慢
Oh, stuff moving slow.
是故意有人磨时间吧
Somebody making it move slower.
蒂博格
Teodoro.
去楼下的理发师那边给我准备下
Set up something at the barber downstairs for me now.
遵命 老大 没有问题
Yes, sir. No problem at all.
告诉那贱货
You tell that bitch
要是再用剃刀割到我 就要她好看
she nick me with the razor again, I'm gonna use it 'pon her.
你还活着
You're still alive.
你依然可爱动人
And you're still lovely.
拜托 我都三天没洗澡了
Oh, please, I haven't showered in three days.
不管你身上什么味 都是成熟味
Whatever you smell like, it's a significant upgrade.
当我和你失去联系后 我
When I didn't hear from you, I
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
-我提醒过你这会有些 -我知道 只是
I warned you it might be a bit I know, I know. It's just
每次他们拖出尸身来
every time they dragged out a body
看着我
Look at me.
我向你保证 离开这后生活绝不会这样的
I promise you when I leave this place, it won't be like that.
好吧
Okay.
你找到我的书了吗?
Now, were you able to find my book?
是的
Yeah.
但是有个家伙
But there was this guy.
他跟踪了我
He followed me.
怎么样的人?
What guy?
我也不认识
I don't know.
他有没有伤到你?
Did he hurt you?
没有
No,
但是他把书夺走了
but he took it.
对不起 辜负你了
I'm sorry.
我不知道该怎么办好
I didn't know what to do.
他长什么样?
-What did he look like? -Um
光头 块头很大
shaved head,kind of big.
他让我告诉你 书在斯科菲尔德的哥哥手上
He said to tell you that Scofield's brother has it now.
-斯科菲尔德是谁? -好吧
Who's Scofield? Okay.
斯科菲尔德是谁?
Who's Scofield? Hmm?
没什么特别的
No one.
他就是 和我一起工作的家伙
He's just, um he's someone I'm working with.
他会帮我离开这里
He's gonna help me get out of here.
他是律师吗?
He's a lawyer?
基本上是吧
Basically.
这就是为何你让他拿到书
That's why you want him to have the book.
听着索菲亚 你知道的越少就越安全
Look, Sofia, the less you know about this, the safer you'll be.
我知道的越少就越帮不了你
The less I know, the less help I'll be.
说的没错
Exactly.
我就想你回避一段时间行吗 宝贝?
I just need you to lay low for a while. Okay, sweetheart?
詹姆斯 这到底怎么回事?
What the hell is going on, James?
这书到底有什么玄机?
What is so important about this book?
没有
Nothing.
不过是有些笔记罢了
It just has notes in it,
比如电话号码之类的
you know, phone numbers.
也就是朋友的朋友 想法把我弄出去
It's people who know people who are going to help me get out of here.
你在撒谎
You're lying.
我为何要对你撒谎?
Why would I lie to you?
你是我唯一能信任的人
You're the only person in the world that I can trust.
过来点
Come here.
现在我只要你信任我
Now, I just need you to trust me.
然后呢?
And do what?
没有然后
Nothing.
请在这签下字
Sign out, please
臭小子 你在找东西?
You looking for something, blanquito?
是的 我在找
Yeah, yeah, I am, I am.
你在找什么东西?
What you looking for then?
就想找些 能消磨时间的东西
Just a little, uh little something to pass the time.
你有钱吗?
You got paper?
下楼去失物招领处找找
Go down to the lost and found with the rest of them.
他们会让你满意的
They'll hook you up proper.
行
All right.
我发现你在别人的地盘找东西
I find you sniffing around where you don't belong,
再这样 你就会和我去决斗
you'll find yourself in that ring again against me.
你根本没有胜机
I don't like your odds.
我给你看看这个
I want you to check something out, all right?
看她的左手 好像在指着什么东西
Look at her left hand like she's pointing at something.
你最好和我表弟说 让他准备好
Well, you'd better tell my cousin he'd better make himself available.
他缺钱总比让我失去耐心要好
Better him short money than me short patience.
听明白了?
No comprende, boy?
手机要去充电
I need a charge.
蒂博格
Teodoro,
快去 给我准备好换洗衣服
go on, get me laundry, no?
没问题 差点忘了 我和理发师说过了
Sure thing, boss oh, almost forgot. Uh, I talked to the barber.
她下午两点能为您服务
She's gonna squeeze you in today around 2:00.
老大 如果这能让你开心起来的话
If that pleases you, patrón.
不错
Patrón.
我觉得你该做出正确选择赎罪了
I think it's time you made good on all the bad you've done, Theodore.
我们之间做个交易
You and me, we're going to make a deal.
勒齐有个手机
Lechero has a cell phone.
我需要那手机
I need it.
没有问题
No problem.
需要我在内部帮你做手脚?
Shall I turn water into wine while I'm at it?
还是把那家伙的老妈给睡了?
Maybe give the guy's mother a good rodgering?
她可能太老了 不对你胃口
She'd be a little old for your tastes, no?
小心点
Careful, Pretty.
别自己惹祸上身
Don't bite the hand you trying to get fed out of.
我没有在找麻烦 我是在找寻帮助
I'm not looking for food, I'm looking for a favor.
我干吗要帮你?
Why the hell should I do you a favor, huh?
因为我不像他们 非常了解你的为人
Cause unlike your new compadres, I know who you are,
知道你都干了什么 对谁干的
what you've done and who you've done it to.
不如挑明直说了吧
Let me get this straight.
你是说你想要告发我?
You're saying you gonna tell on me?
我要说的是 这是个信教的国家
this here is a religious country,
我宁可赌一把 看看巴拿马良民
and I'm willing to bet the good folks down in Panama
会如何善待强奸犯
don't take too kindly to rapists
兼恋童癖的
and pedophiles.
你愿意和我赌上一把吗?
You want to bet against me?
兄弟 听着
Listen, mate.
这是我目前知道的情况
Here's what I know so far.
我知道你的兄弟在外面想办法把我们弄出去
I know you've got a brother helping on the outside,
我还知道他跑去见我女朋友了
I know he ran into my girlfriend,
还从她那里拿走了我的一本书
and I know he took a book from her that belongs to me.
把书还给我
I'd like it back.
那本书有那么特别吗
What's so special about this book?
除非能想办法出去
Well, unless it has directions out of this prison,
我认为你不会真的在乎这本书
I don't think it should really matter to you.
你根本不知道我在乎什么
You don't know what matters to me.
我们出去了就把书还给你
You can get that book back when we get out of Sona.
是吗?
Oh, yeah?
那究竟啥时候我们能出去呢
And when the hell is that exactly?
到现在为止 我根本看不出能逃出生天
Because so far I haven'seen bollocks in the way of breaking out of here.
我来告诉你目前掌握的情况
Let me tell you what I know so far.
有帮干尽坏事的家伙
Some very bad people who have done
希望你活着
some very bad things want you alive
并且从这里出去 我的良知告诉我
and out of this prison, which is why every bone
我不应该帮他们把你弄出去
in my body is telling me to do the opposite.
那你为啥还要这么做
Then why are you doing it?
有人拿走了你的书你就不高兴了
You're upset because someone took a book from you.
这是那帮家伙从我这里抢走的
This is what they took from me.
所以 跟你直说了
So let's be clear.
我在乎的是她 不是你
This is what matters to me, not you
也不是你的什么书
and not your book.
喂
Hello.
表哥 还行吧
Cousin, how is it?
你好啊 奥古斯特
Hey, Augusto.
你说呢 兄弟
You tell me, man.
生意就是那样 老大
Oh, business is cyclical, don dada.
有时候好 有时候坏
Ebbs and flows, ebbs and flows, you know.
看起来最近不怎么样啊?
Seems like there's more ebbing than flowing these days, huh?
你说呢
You think?
我跟你说说我的想法
I'm gonna tell you what I think, man.
我看有个黑心鬼想抢走我的生意
I think a black heart is trying to steal my business.
趁我不在的时候想干坏事了
Is taking advantage of my situation.
我有没有说错啊?
If there are mistakes have been made,
对我坦诚点
all I need is some honesty, man.
不是这样的 我发誓
No mistakes, patron, I swear.
那看起来问题不是出在你这儿了
Well, maybe the problem isn't on the outside.
这么说问题就是
Maybe the problem is
奥古斯特
Augusto.
奥古斯特?
Augusto?
没电了
Battery dead.
他妈的
The bloodfire
电话的插头为啥被拔掉了?
How me phone come unplugged? Huh?
电池没电了
My battery dead.
你们啥都不知道
None of you know nothing, huh?
你是马宏先生?
Mr. Mahone?
我叫劳尔·达林达
Raul Darinda.
我被指派担任你的义务辩护律师
I am the public defender appointed to your case.
这 嗯
That's, uh
很好 太好了
uh, that's great, that's great.
我准备了一些
I-I've been putting together
笔记 我想
some notes that I
我有好消息要告诉你
Looks like I h some great news.
案子的开庭时间定下来了
We got you a trial date.
那可真 感谢上帝
That's really th-thank God.
感谢上帝 什么时候
Thank God when?
6月13号
June 13.
不 不 等等 等等 是
Oh, no, no, wait, wait, wait, th-the
13号 13号? 那是上个礼拜啊
13th, 13th, that was last week.
怎么回事 我们错过了?
What, we missed it?
不是的 是明年的6月13号 马宏先生
June 13 of next year, Mr. Mahone.
明年
Next year.
这算什么好消息
How the hell is that great news?
对于外国公民来说
It usually takes two and a half years
开庭通常需要等2年半的
for a non-citizen to get before a judge.
我这里有个叫迈克·斯科菲尔德的人
I've got a guy in, in here, his name is Michael Scofield
他愿意作证 是他嫁祸给我的
and, and he will testify that he set me up
是他把毒品藏在船上的
and that he put the drugs on the boat.
这些情况都会被考虑的
Which will all be taken into consideration
一年之后
A year from now
请不要那么激动 马宏先生
I'm going to have to ask you to calm down, Mr. Mahone.
根本就是废话
It's open and shut.
你简直就是笨蛋 现在有人可以证明我
It's a no-brainer for you. I got a guy who can cop to The notion
你讲的犯人甲代犯人乙承担罪责的主意
of one inmate taking the fall for another
在这里很常见了
isot exactly fresh
而且通常只能说明那个人被迫
and usually means someone was pressured
承认这些事情的
into the confession.
好吧 还有个事 劳尔
Well, here's the thing, Raul.
我需要一些药
I require a certain medication
在这里 他们不能提供这些东西
that they, well, they just don't provide here,
我是
and I am
这样说吧 这会
Let's just say thatt would be good
对大家都好
for everybody
如果我可以得到一些药的话
if, um, if I got this medication.
你是在威胁我吗
Is that a threat?
不是的
No.
只是实际情况 这是
No, it's a reality, it's, it's
这种药叫Varatril 如果你
It's called Varatril and, and, and if you
听着 如果你想让我帮你偷偷搞点毒品
Look, if you are asking me to smuggle drugs
进去 那么
into this prison, then
不 不 我没有 我不是让你偷偷给我
No, no, I'm not I'm not asking you to smuggle it.
我只是说如果你可以弄到
I'm just saying if you could get
再见吧 马宏先生
Good luck, Mr. Mahone.
等等 你这个混蛋
So Wait, you son of a bitch
老大 差不多2点了
Uh, boss, it's 2:00.
好吧
All right.
要带电话吗 老大
You want your cell phone, brother?
不用了 半个小时就回来了
No, just be a half hour.
电话留着充电吧
Leave it for charge.
你有30分钟时间 26分的时候就还回去
You have 30 minutes 26 minutes he'll get back
如果你不把电话
If that phone ain't back
还回充电座 我们都会完蛋 明白了吗?
on the cradle, we're both dead, you hear me?
我不会一个人背这个黑锅的
Cause my Alabama ass is not going down alone.
喂
Yeah?
让莎拉照这个号码打过来
Tell Sara to call me at this number.
好的 不过那个苏珊
All right, but this Susan chick,
她还没有同意 兄弟
she hasn't even agreed to it yet, man.
什么 我只有25分钟
What? I only have 25 minutes
可以用这个电话 林肯
with this phone, Linc.
我马上去见她 不过听着
I'm meeting her right no but listen,
圣丽塔 这个地方可不小
Santa Rita ain't a one-horse town.
我说 希望莎拉可以
I mean, God, I hope that Sara can give us
给我们点线索
some kind of clue as to where
让她打给我就行
Just get her on the line.
想办法让她跟我通话 好吗
Just get her on the line, okay?
我就这么一个机会
This is a one-shot deal.
我知道了 兄弟
Yeah, I know, man.
只有23分钟了
23 minutes.
我快到了
I'm nearly there.
看起来这鞋不合脚啊
Hey, looks like we got off on the wrong foot here.
我可不喜欢暴力
I'm not a violent guy.
我只想要那只鞋
It's just that I need that shoe.
我都走不了路了 这地方
I can't hardly walk, and this place
可以把人变坏的
it changes people.
我都不知道你叫什么
Oh, I never even got your name.
我叫皮萨齐奥
Pistachio.
皮萨齐奥
Pistachio?
这可是个
Now, that's just
这可是个好听的名字
That's a beautiful name.
你想怎么样呢
What you want then?
我想我们是不是可以做个交易
Well, I was hoping we could make some kind of a deal.
交易
Trade.
对于你唯一可以提供的东西
The only thing you got to sell,
我不敢兴趣
me no want to buy.
我喜欢的男人是要再
I like me men a little more
英语怎么说来着
How you say, uh ?
-不那么胖 -胖? 这可都是肌肉
Not fat. Fat? This is all muscle.
我可以证明给你看的
And I'd prove it to you if I didn't think
如果你可以把东西给我的话
you'd take things south of the border.
别激动
Now, hold on.
我们只是谈谈
This is a negotiation.
没必要 我可不是要捅你
You don't have to I no gonna cut you.
我来客人了
I got clients.
滚
Get.
老大 欢迎光临
Welcome, patron.
非常高兴为你服务
I'm so honored to have you.
快点剔完头吧
Let's make this quick.
你去哪儿了
Where the hell have you been?
女人总需要打扮的
Well, a girl's got to look her best.
你不是在耍什么把戏吧
This ain't a game, sister.
你最好给我安分点
You'd better back the hell up.
现在很明显你需要我们
It's becoming pretty clear you need us,
所以不要像你掌控一切的样子
so stop pretending you're in charge,
在我们需要的时候 给我们想要的东西
and give us what we want when we want it.
电话铃一响就开始
Starting with the damn phone call.
喂
Hello?
是我
It's me.
你怎么样了
How are you?
我很累
I'm tired.
你在哪?
Where ? Where are you?
说来话长
It's a long story.
出事后 我哪也不能出现
As it turns out, I don't appear to be going anywhere.
我知道
I know. I know.
我正在处理那个问题
I'm working on that.
莎拉 我常常想恋我们一起聊天
Listen, Sara, I miss how we used to talk.
你还记得 我们怎么聊的吗
Do you remember how we used to talk?
恩
Yes.
好的
good.
好的 因为今天我看到了你的照片
Good, because I saw your picture today,
我想你知道我了解
and I want you to know I understand
我知道你现在所处的困难环境
I understand the difficult place you're in.
Michael 听着 我
Michael, listen, I
我不想你这么想
I don't want you to think like that.
为什么
Why is that?
你要知道
You have to know
已经来不及了
it a lost cause.
LJ和我 我们都很清楚
LJ and I we can see it now.
已经来不及了 注定要失败的
It's a lost cause.
你知道吗
Do you understand?
不 不 我不理解
No, no. No, I I don't. I don't.
帮我理清楚
Help me understand. Help me understand.
唯一能帮助的就是 也许你需要更多时间
All I can think of to help is, maybe you just need more time?
就像 就像
It's like It's like
他们子夜才能和我们接头
they're giving you until midnight,
但是我坐在3点钟位置
and I'm sitting here 3:00 a.m.
他们命令我挂电话了
They're saying I have to hang up.
莎拉 我爱你
Sara, I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
莎拉?
Sara?
林肯 他们从没在圣丽塔
Linc, they were never in Santa Rita.
什么? 她说来不及了
What? She said it was a lost cause.
她说她已经知道来不及了
She said she could see it was a lost cause.
然后?
So?
patr saint的失败原因就是圣丽塔
The patr saint of lost causes is Saint Rita.
她从来没有告诉我们他们在哪
She was never telling us where they were.
她告诉我们从他们那可以看到什么
She was telling us what they could see from where they were.
他在归途了 快把手机给我 哥们
He's on his way. We need to get that phone back, like, rapido.
最后一件事 林肯
One more thing, Linc.
-快点美人 -闭嘴
Come on, Pretty Stall them
她说他们好像子夜才能和我们接头
She said, it's like they were giving us until midnight,
但是她说她坐在3点处
but she was sitting at 3:00 a.m.
这到底算什么意思?
What the hell does that mean?
我不知道 也许他们离钟之类的很近
I don't know. Maybe they're near a clock or something.
我知道的就这些
That's all I got.
我要走了
Listen, I got to go.
都交给你了
It's up to you.
别惹他
Leave him alone, huh?
勒齐
Lechero
你需要知道这事
There's something you should know.
什么
What?
我想那个理发师他
I think that barber might have
划到我的头了吗?
Uh cut me?
恩
Hmm.
没有划到
No.
没有 我看错了
No. My mistake.
我
I
你知道吗 实际上 这个
You know, in fact that-that there
也许是我见过理的最好的了
might just be the best shave I have ever seen.
伙计 你看起来哪天你也要理一个
Boy, you look like you need one today.
也许我也要理一个
I might just do that.
四处走走 看看
Can't be walking around, looking all, uh, bhuttu.
你是谁
Who is this?
查出和这个号码有关的所有情况
Find out everything you can about this number.
嘿
Yo
别动
Don't move.
我想知道
I want to know what
你对詹姆斯·惠斯勒做了什么
the hell you're doing to James Whistler.
什么也没做
I'm doing nothing to James Whistler.
我们现在在同一条船上对吧
Listen, we're on the same team, all right?
别紧张
Take it easy. Just
把刀拿开好吗
Put the knife away.
把 刀 拿 开
我们不是一路人
We're not on the same team.
你想那小子从索纳监狱出来对吧
You want your boy out of Sona, right?
-对吧? -当然
-Right? -Of course.
那好 我就是要帮他越狱的家伙
Well, I'm one of the guys who's going to break him out.
不 我今天早上和他说了
No.No. I talked to him this morning.
他有个律师
He has a lawyer.
我不知道他对你说了什么 也不知他的真实身份
I don't know what he's told you, or who he is.
我知道他是谁
I know who he is.
好吧 他是别人都热盼他出来的渔夫
Right. A fisherman that people want out so badly
那些人甚至绑架我儿子来交换他
they're willing to kidnap my son to get him.
听着
Listen,
你需要和他谈谈
you need to talk to him.
You need to talk to him.
去哪里 朋友?
Where to, my friend?
我在找一个雕像纪念碑
I'm looking for a statue, a monument.
圣 圣丽塔 这上面这么说
Uh, Santa, Santa Rita. Says it's in here some
圣女之像
The lady of the lost causes.
是的 就是那
Yeah, that's it.
那是红灯区
The red light district.
你要去找乐子么?
You looking to party?
你好么?
You all right?
你想要什么?
What do you want?
我来告诉你 不需要提防我
Let you know you don't have to watch your back.
确定我也不需要警惕你
Make sure I don't have to watch mine.
我的命曾经是可以让人从这里出去的门票
My head was a free tick out of here.
我不记恨
I don't begrudge anyone
那些曾经尝试要我命的人
who did what they had to do to try and get it.
除此之外
Besides
你
you, uh,
时不时在这里也会需要一个朋友的
never know when you'll need a friend in this place.
你从哪里来?
Where are you from?
博德曼市 俄亥俄州
Boardman, Ohio.
我来自卡尔巴里
Kalbarri.
澳大利亚的捕鱼胜地
Australia. Good fishing.
你去过?
You've been?
路过
Passed through.
世界真小
Small world.
你到巴拿马来干嘛呢?
What the hell are you doing in Pana?
我不想谈这个
I'm not really in the mood.
你是那个警察 对么?
You're that cop, are you?
你知道我曾经看着斯科菲尔德
You know, I was looking at that Scofield.
想不出来为什么他看起来那么脸熟
I was trying to figure why he looked so bloody familiar.
现在 听到你的声音
Then, just now, hearing your voice,
我记得看过最初的新闻发布会
I rememberatching the press when that first happened.
现在 你们又聚到了一起
And now you're in here together.
世界真小
Small world.
你想把他弄出去吗?
You trying to get him out of here?
引渡或者用其他什么方式?
Extradition or what?
我现在不干那个工作了
I'm not really in that line of work anymore.
他是个什么人呢?
What's he all about?
我是指斯科菲尔德
Scofield?
我是说 他危险么?
I mean, is he dangerous?
关你什么事?
What's it to you?
只是好奇
Just curious
我要相处的家伙是什么类型的
as to what kind of chap I'm dealing with.
我想这取决于你为什么要跟他打交道了
I guess that depends on why you'd be dealing with him.
如我所说 你不知道何时
Like I said never know when you'll
就需要朋友
Need a friend.
关于斯科菲尔德是这样的
See, one thing about Scofield is that,
对于他关心的人
for those that he cares about,
他会为他们做任何事情
he'll do just about anything.
如果他不喜欢你 他随随便便就可以整死你
But he'll screw you three ways to Sunday if he doesn't.
现在我知道你是属于哪一类了
I can guess which side you ended up on.
很好
Well
交流愉快
Thanks for the chat.
你知道么 我只是过来
You know, I really just came by
不 因为你想
No, you came by cause
从我这里了解更多关于斯科菲尔德的事
you wanted to find out more about Scofield,
这没问题
but that's cool.
我们之间没问题了
We're squared away.
就在那 她在那儿
There. She is there.
这是镇上唯一和圣丽塔有关的东西吗?
That the only thing about Saint Rita in this town?
这我就不知道了 朋友
That I do not know, my friend.
请问?
Excuse me?
这周围有有钟么? 钟 恩
Is there a clock around here? A clock, uh
不 我不知道
No. No comprendo.
打扰下
Excuse me?
你看见过这些人么?
Have you seen these people?
没有
Huh? No? No.
钟
Clock.
她说 好像是说一直到子夜
She said, it's like they were giving us until midnight.
一直要等到12点
Give us till 12.
她在3点钟方向
But she was sitting 3:00 a.m.
三
Three
莎拉
Sara.
爸爸
Dad
爸爸 爸爸 爸爸
Dad Dad Dad
LJ
LJ 莎拉
LJ Sara
什么时候?
When?
我找到那地方了
It was the right place.
我只是没有及时达到那里
I just couldn't get to it in time.
你看到他们了么? 他们好么?
Did you see them? Do they look all right?
就我看到的而言 很好
As far as I could tell, yeah.
那个你可以留着
You can keep that.
把这作为纪念
Keep it as a souvenir
当一切结束后送给莎拉
and give it to Sara when this is all done.
Michael 我们可以做到
Michael, we can do this.
不然他们不会费那么多精力
They wouldn't have gone to all this trouble
把你弄到这里来
to put you in here
如果不可能的话 他们也不会费尽周折
if it wasn't possible to get out.
我们可以做到
We can do this.
We can do it.
我想我们需要谈谈
I think we need to talk.
你的朋友 照片中的那个人
Your friend, the one in the picture,
你说是她是你在这里的原因?
you say she's the reason you're here?
如此这般 我们就有共同点了
Then we have something in common.
你哥哥在外面遇到的那个女人
The woman your brother met on the outside,
她叫索菲亚
her name is Sofia.
她是我在这里的原因
She's the reason I'm here.
那好 除非这个索非亚也被枪指着
Well, unless this Sofia is being held at gunpoint,
我们没有共同点
we got nothing in common.
但是你也许可以告诉我
But maybe you can start by telling me
为什么中情局对你这么感兴趣
why the Company's so interested in you.
什么中情局?
What company?
我没时间和你玩
I don't have time for games.
好 好 听着
Okay, okay, look.
我在这里和
Look, I've been splitting time between here
西北太平洋之间跑船
and the Pacific Northwest running charters.
捕鱼是吗
Fishing?
对 捕鱼
Fishing,
观光 只要可以赚钱的都干
sightseeing whatever was paying the bloody rent.
一年前 我带了一个人出海
Now, abo year ago, I took a guy out.
他是个自然科学家什么的
He was some sort of naturalist.He was, uh
他采集水样测量
he was taking water samples, measurements.
为了什么?
What for?
我不知道
I don't know.
我对此毫不关心
I didn't really care as long as the check cleared,
但有件事情
but here's the thing.
几个月后 我接到了一个电话
A few months later, I get a call from somebody
想知道我带那人去了什么地方
wanting to know where I took the guy.
我告诉他们我不记得了
And I told them I couldn't remember.
但是后来
But then these, um
政府模样的人
then these government types,
他们来找我 开始问我问题
they started showing up at my flat asking questions,
我不知道怎么做
and I didn't know what to do.
所以我就躲了起来 就逃到了巴拿马
So I got low, I came down to Panama,
我一直和索菲亚住在一起
and I moved in with Sofia full time.
直到 酒吧打架事件的发生
Until Until the fight at the bar.
是的 我最终到了这里
Yeah, and then I end up here,
以前那帮人又来探视我
where those same people show up at visitation
说他们会把我弄出去
saying they're going to get me out.
作为回报 我把他们带回之前去的地方
And when they do, I'm to take them to the same place
就是我带那个家伙去的那个地方
that I took that guy.
这就是为何需要被你哥抢走的书的原因
That's why I need the book your brother copped.
那是我航程日志
It's my trip log.
我在空白处作了标记 坐标 路标之类
I write notes in the margins, you know, coordinates, landmarks.
我需要循着原路返回
I need to retrace my steps and find that location.
-我没有选择 -这真是个有趣的故事
I don't have a choice. That's a really interesting story,
但是如果那本书真的如你所说
but if that book's as valuable as you say it is,
我应该留着它
maybe I should hold onto it for a little while,
直到我跟他们做完这个交易
make sure they hold up their end of the deal.
你还不理解 是么?
You don't get this, do you?
我需要时间去做
I need time to be able to
我唯一要做的事情就是带你离开这里
The only thing I'm responsible for is getting you out of here.
你们之间的事和我无关
Whatever's between you and them is between you and them.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry
没关系
All right.
你想到该怎么做了吗
Do you have any idea how we're going to do this?
我一直听说没人从这里出去过
All I keep hearing is how no one gets out of this place.
我想我也听过
I think I've heard that one before.
甘蔗好甜
The sugarcane's so sweet.
芒果也很甜 女人也
The mangoes' so sweet, the women so
如果这不是演艺人员
Well, if it isn't the entertainer.
给我们说个笑话如何
How about a joke for us, boy?
伙计 现在不是时候 我得
Not now, fellas, I got to get
何不给我们跳个舞呢?
Why don't you do a little dance for us, huh?
比如一段热舞?
How about a little jig, huh?
或许你要借只手吧?
Maybe you need an extra hand?
你说的真对
You got me.
没错
Yeah, that's right.
我知道你的伎俩
I do get you, boy.
你骗得了他 但骗不了我
You might've fooled him, but you're not fooling me.
老大 打扰了
Excuse me, boss.
我让你别进来的
I asked you for privacy.
我只是来
Just came in here to, to
谢谢你让我在这里帮忙的
thank you for giving me a hand up in here,
尽管如此 我只是想
but if it's all the same, I'd just like to be
减轻我的责任
relieved of my duties.
你在说什么?
Wh are you talking about?
有些
There's some, um
关于忠诚的问题 我还不想
loyalty issues going on, and I do not want to end up
在我对你的忠诚和
torn between my fidelity to you and the reality
被人指着鼻子的现实中做出取舍
of having to keep my nose clean.
我很早就知道
I've been around long enough to know
多米诺牌开始倒塌的时候
that when the dominoes start falling,
往往会怪新来的人
it's the new guy that gets blamed
撞到桌子
for bumping the table.
你最好别拐弯抹角 有话直说
You better stop spinning and start talking straight.
不
No
我不是打小报告的人
I ain't no rat.
我不是让你
I'm not asking you to be
打小报告
a rat.
我是让你做我朋友 好吗?
I'm asking you to be a friend, huh?
就像我之前那样
As I've been with you.
好的
Okay.
早先我在散步
I was walking earlier,
我听到一些声音
and I heard some voices talking
让勒齐见鬼去吧
about,"To hell with Lechero.
我想要我那份
I want my cut."
我现在不能说他们是谁
Now, I couldn't tell who it was,
但当我走到角落的时候 我发现
but when I got around the corner, I recognized the faces
那些脸我很熟悉 我在这里见过
the very same faces I've seen in this room.
我在这里得不到什么好处
Now, I got nothing to gain here, okay?
我不是什么人物
I'm a nobody
也成不了什么大人物
w-with no hope of being anyone.
但你身边的人
But those that surround you have
你下台后会得到一切
everything to gain if you fall.
我想我们两清了
I hope this makes us even.
但是我给你的
But what I've given you
不是帮一个忙就能回报的
can't be repaid with one favor.
所以我拒绝你的要求
So I deny your request,
你可以继续跟着我
and you're going to stay on
做我的耳目
as my ears.
当我不在的时候
You'll report back to me everything you hear
把你听到的都告诉我
when I'm not around.
Michael 过的怎样?
How've you been, Michael?
显然比某些人好
Better than some, apparently.
你知道 这太有意思了
You know, it's interesting
为什么你对你现在的住宿条件
how you don't seem rattled at all
一点也不恼火?
by our current accommodations.
是不是因为你觉得不会和他们在一起很久?
Could it be because maybe you're not planning on being in them much longer?
阿历克斯 还是和我之前告诉你的一样
It's like I told you before, Alex,
我们之间交情已了
this is the end of the line for both of us.
那这样吧
How about this?
我说错了你就不让我说
You stop me when I'm wrong.
那个中情局要你活着留在巴拿马
The Company wanted you here in Panama alive,
但是又诬陷你谋杀 而且是些奇怪理由
but framed for murder, and then for so for some strange reason
你很在意那个惠斯勒的生死
you seemed to really care about the fate of this Whistler guy,
我来告诉你一些事情吧
and I got to tell you something,
他对你也很好奇
he's really curious about you, too.
我们仔细想想 你有什么特殊才能让中情局
Let's see, what special talents do you have that the Company
让中情局觉得你活着比死了
might make the decision that you're worth
更有意义?
more to them alive than dead?
迈克 你怎么回答?
Huh, what do you say there, Mike?
我说到重点了吧
Am I getting warm yet?
我想你该吃药了
I think you better pop another pill,
因为全是胡扯
cause that's crazy.
那么你不介意我杀了他吧
Oh, so you don't mind if I kill him?
惠斯勒?
Whistler?
我想问题在于"中情局到底在意什么?"
I think the question is,"What would the Company mind?"
问题是"他们会对你做什么"
The question is,"What would they do to you?"
对你所爱的人做什么
To the ones you love?
阿历克斯 小心点
Be careful, Alex.
忙碌的一天?
Busy day?
没我希望的那样忙碌
Not as busy as I'd hoped.
你想要试试
Look, you had to try.
换作我 也会做跟你一样的事
I probably would've done the same thing myself if I were you.
但是让我们彻底说清楚
But let's be perfectly clear.
你以后都不可以再做这样的事
You're never going to try anything like that again.
我明白
I understand.
好 你最好真的明白了
Yeah, but just to make sure that you do,
我给你留了点东西在车库里
I left you a little something in the garage.